(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-28T00:26:13.736575",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
いつも迷惑ばかりかけるけど
Always causing trouble for you on and on
いつも散々困らせちゃうけど
Always driving you crazy, though
それでも隣にいてくれる君のそばに添えた
Still, you stay right by my side...
曖昧な言葉じゃ
Vague words alone
真面目な君には伝わらない
Won't reach a serious person like you
頑丈なそのハートを
That sturdy heart of yours
覗いてみたい
I want to peek inside
溶かしてみたい
I want to melt it down
そんな時こんな魔法はどうかな？
What kind of magic works at a time like this?
何が出るかな？
What will come out?
やっちゃえ！
Let's do it!
せーの！
Ready, go!
try try try
あやふやだって
Even if it's vague
いいの！いいの！
It's fine! It's fine!
witch one to pick
Which one to pick?
watch me do magic
あらら想像以上の展開
Oh my, an unexpected turn of events
もう止められないのよ
I can't stop anymore
ごめんなさい
I'm so sorry
溢れる思いで空回り
Spinning my wheels with overflowing feelings
振りかけるhappyなイメージで
Sprinkling happy images
振り回すfancyなマジック
Wielding a fancy magic
もっと君にくどくど言われちゃうけどほらこんだday by dayがいい
Even if you nag me more and more, day by day is best
あの日からfalling in love with you
Ever since that day, falling in love with you
変わらないからずっとonly youだからほらうだうだしてる場合じゃないの
It won't change, always only you, so this is no time to hesitate
掴めハッピーエンディング
Grab your happy ending
いつまでも隣で笑っていたいのよ
I want to keep smiling right by your side
いつも仲間はずれで
Always left out of the group
ひとりぼっちの毎日
Living lonely days all by myself
そんな私の前に現れた君は同じ寂しさを抱えている
And you who appeared before me bear that same loneliness
とてもとても優しい人
Such a very, very kind person
今も心配ごとは多いけど
Even now, there are still many worries
もう私も君もひとりじゃない
Neither you nor I are alone anymore
騒がしくて愛しいこの日々がずっと続きますように
May these lively, precious days continue forever
three, two, one!
飛ばせhappyなイメージ
Fly out those happy images
とびきりfancyなマジック
With an outstanding fancy magic
おかしくって愛しい
So strangely lovely,
この日々がずっと続きますように
May these days continue forever
とばせハッピーなイメージ
Let loose a happy image
とびきりのファッションマジック
A standout fashion magic
また君にクドクド言われそうだけど
Though you'll probably nag me again
そんなのいっぱいテイクイットイージー
Even so, take it easy!
あの日から Fall in love with you
Ever since that day, fall in love with you
気づいてほしいの Love with you
I want you to notice, love with you
だからこそ うだうだしてる場合じゃないの
That's why this isn't the time to dawdle
次はどんなプランニング
What's the next planning?
そしてまた今日もハプニング
And another happening today
明日はどんなおかしなことが起こるかな
I wonder what funny things will happen tomorrow
ずっと隣で見ててね
Watch me from right beside me
ハッピーなイメージ
Happy image
ファッションマジック
Fashion magic
ハッピーなイメージ
Happy image
ファッションマジック
Fashion magic
みんな！今日は、私の誕生日ライブに来てくれて、ありがとうございます！
Everyone! Thank you so much for coming to my birthday live today!
改めてまして、もぐもぐ、おかゆです！
Once again, I'm Mogu Mogu Okayu!
ホロライブゲーマーズの猫又おかゆでーす！
I'm Nekomata Okayu from Hololive Gamers!
本日は、こちら、ハッシュタグ「猫又おかゆ生誕祭2026」で、いっぱいつぶやいてください！
Today, please tweet a lot using the hashtag "#NekomataOkayuBirthday2026"!
ライブ終わったあとすぐ見に行っちゃうんだからね。ふふっ
Because I'll go check them right after the live ends. Hehe.
そして、みんな見て！今回のライブは「みあどクッキー」というタイトルを付けました！
And everyone, look! I titled this live "Miad Cookie"!
「みあど」って言うのは、「君を」っていう意味があるんだけど、なんで「みあど」って付けたのかなとか、考えながらライブを見てくれると嬉しいなって思っているよ。
"Miad" means "you", and I hope you enjoy watching the live while wondering why I named it that.
そして、見て！このステージ、とってもかわいいでしょ？
And look! Isn't this stage super cute?
でも、かわいいだけじゃないんだよ。
But it's not just cute.
すごいね、曲によってガラーっと雰囲気変わるように作っていただいたので、そこもね、注目してみてください。「えっ？」ってなるかもしれないね。
It changes atmosphere completely depending on the song, so please pay attention to that too. You might go "Eh?!"
そして、ゲストも、今回ももりだくさんでございます！わくわく、ドキドキ。いや僕も、今から、ちゃんと、ふ、振り付けとか歌とか、いけるのかなって思いつつも、
And guests, plenty of them this time too! Exciting, nervous. Well, even I am wondering if I can properly do the choreography and singing...
ではね、みんなと楽しく自分の誕生日をお祝いできたらなと思っております。
So, I hope we can all happily celebrate my birthday together.
そして最後に、みんなに喜んでもらえるような告知を用意してあるので、ぜひ最後まで楽しんでもらえればなと思っております！
And lastly, I've prepared an announcement that will make everyone happy, so I hope you'll enjoy it all the way to the end!
次の曲、行ってみよっか！
Shall we go to the next song?
ねえあたし知ってるよ 君がひとり
Hey, I know you're all alone
知ってるの
I know it
知ってるよ
ビクンビクン震えてさ
You're shaking and twitching
声も漏れ漏れなんだわ
Your voice is leaking out
正直に言っちゃいよ
Honestly just admit it
バレてんだし言っちゃいよ
Your cover's blown, just admit it
聞いてるの？
Are you listening?
普通普通 恥ずかしい？
Normally embarrassing?
みんな隠しているだけ
Everyone's just hiding it
ねえあたし知ってるよ 君がひとり涙し
Hey, I know you're crying all alone
知ってるの
I know it
知ってるよ
グスングスンへこんでさ
Sniffling and feeling down
弱音吐いてから in the night
Uttering complaints in the night
朝が来るまで一緒にこうす
Until morning comes, let's course together
もっと泣いたって
Even if you cry more
何度だって受け止めてあげる
I'll catch you no matter how many times
もう我慢しないでいっぱい出してね
Don't hold back, let it all out
おねがい 君がほしいの 慰めさせて
WAHI! Please, I want you, let me comfort you
シェイクシェイク 愛の才能で 泣いてくれなきゃ枯れてしまう
Shake Shake with the talent of love, if you don't cry I'll wither away
濡れていたい 泣いてんでしょ
I want to get wet, you're crying, right?
舐め取って飲み干したいんだってば WAHI!
I want to lick it up and drink it all down, WAHI!
おねがい 君がほしいの 頼りにして欲しいの
Please, I want you, I want you to rely on me
なんて最高ね
How amazing
濡れていたい 君の痛い感じでいたい 泣いてんでしょ
I want to get wet, I want to feel your pain, you're crying, right?
吸い取って救いたいんだってば WAHI!
I want to absorb and save you, WAHI!
見たい 見たい 見たい...
I want to see, want to see...
ねぇあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり悔しがってんの知ってるよ
Hey, I know, I know you're all alone and frustrated,
ズキュンズキュン高まるじゃん きみを押すことはやめない
Heart pounding higher, I won't stop pushing you.
ねぇあたし知ってるよ きみはできる子知ってるよ つらい時は
Hey, I know, I know you can do it, when times are tough,
いわいくらいでちょうどいい あたしそれでも好きだよ
Celebrating just enough is fine, I still love you for it.
MWAH! お願いきみが欲しいの 名前を呼んでよ いつだって愛に参上
MWAH! Please, I want you, call my name, always rushing to your love!
きみはひとりだ だから歌う ひとりじゃない もういいでしょ
You're all alone, so I sing—you're not alone, isn't that enough?
ソロプレイはおしまいなんだってば
Solo play is over, you see!
きみがやめるときも あたし側にいるわ
Even when you want to quit, I'll be right by your side.
いつも見守っているわ そうよ怖くないのよ
Always watching over you, yeah, there's nothing to be afraid of.
MWAH! お願いきみが欲しいの なぐさめさせて shake shake
MWAH! Please, I want you, let me comfort you, shake shake,
愛の才能で 泣いてくれなきゃ枯れてしまう 濡れていたいねぇいいでしょ
With the talent of love—if you don't cry, I'll wither away.
なめてって飲み干したいんだってば
I want to lick it all up and drink it dry, you see!
MWAH! お願いきみが欲しいの 頼り散らして shake up
MWAH! Please, I want you, rely on me scattered around, shake up,
なんて最高ね 分けてくれなきゃきみの痛い感じてたい泣かせてたい
How amazing—if you don't share, I want to feel your pain.
吸い取って救いたいんだってば
I want to suck it up and save you, you see!
ねぇあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり涙流してるの知ってるよ
Hey, I know, I know you're crying all alone,
グズングズンえきんでさ いわゆる人から in the night
Sobs and whimpers locked inside, far from people in the night.
朝が来るまで一緒コスモッナイ だって何度だって受け止めてあげる
Together until morning comes, cosmo-night, because I'll catch you.
もう我慢しないで出してってば
Just let it all out already!
ながらの優等生 今宵も自分と密会です しんどいわ しんどいわ
An honor student by the way, having a secret meeting with myself tonight.
バズろっつろ合唱 本当は劣等生 あたしはあたしにすっぴょです
Chanting to go viral, actually an underachiever, I'm bare-faced to myself.
しんどいわ しんどいわ もぉいやいやぜっか！
It's so tough, so tough, seriously no more, absolutely not!
心配無用心配無用 これはライルジョークさん
Don't worry, don't worry, this is a Lyle joke,
心配無用冗談も みんなおだてるポップさん まぁまぁそれをさすよ ただの噛み癖ですよ
Don't worry, even jokes, everyone cheering pop star, biting habit.
いいから早く保護をせよや
So hurry up and protect me already!
デビルじゃないデビルじゃないもん 悪魔ほどそうもん
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil! Devils aren't really like that.
あぁ死んじゃった死んじゃった 愛してほしいじゃん
Ah, I died, I died, you want me to love you right?
それでもハマっちゃうなら それでも恋しちゃうなら
Even if you fall for it anyway, even if you fall in love anyway,
あぁ死んじゃった死んじゃった エンジェルエンジェル
Ah, I died, I died, angel, angel!
悲報悲報悲報悲報 きたのいね とべないね
Bad news! You came, right? You can't fly, right?
デビルじゃないデビルじゃないもん
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil!
あぁ死んじゃった死んじゃった 本当の天使スルーしてご臨終
Ah, I died, I died, passing over the real angel straight to the afterlife.
あくまで天使じゃん？ 最強じゃん！
After all, I'm an angel, right? The strongest, right!
切り詰めて寝言の悪因
Cutting corners, bad habits of sleepy talk,
夢が叶うって Uber サラリー
Dreams coming true like an Uber salary,
破産直前の高い方に逆らうんだな
Going against the pricey things right before bankruptcy.
魂の枯れちゃってやめやめ
My soul is withered, stop it, stop it!
光り輝く輪っかでこの首がしまっていく
With a glowing halo, this neck is getting tighter.
嘘つきは緩んでく言えない SOS
Liars loosen up, unspoken SOS.
白い天使被りましょう なりきってしまいましょう
Let's put on a white angel mask, let's play the part completely.
嘘つきばらくになる ほらやっちゃって！
Liars become carefree, come on, just do it!
デビルじゃないデビルじゃないもん
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil!
あぁ死んじゃった死んじゃった
Ah, I died, I died!
それでもうがっちゃうけど それでも嫌っちゃうけど
Even if I get suspicious, even if I end up hating it,
なりきって笑顔でエンジェルエンジェル
Playing the part with a smile, angel, angel!
デビルじゃないデビルじゃないもん 悪魔ほどそうもん あぁ死んじゃった死んじゃった 愛してほしいじゃん
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil! Devils aren't really like that. Ah, I died, I died, you want me to love you right?
それでもハマっちゃうなら それでも恋しちゃうなら
Even if you fall for it anyway, even if you fall in love anyway,
あぁ死んじゃった死んじゃった エンジェルエンジェル
Ah, I died, I died, angel, angel!
悲報悲報悲報悲報 きたのいね とべないね
Bad news! You came, right? You can't fly, right?
デビルじゃないデビルじゃないもん
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil!
あぁ死んじゃった死んじゃった 本当の天使スルーしてご臨終
Ah, I died, I died, passing over the real angel straight to the afterlife.
悲報悲報悲報悲報 見にくいね 映えないね
Bad news! Hard to look at, unphotogenic!
デビルじゃないデビルじゃないもん
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil!
あぁ死んじゃった死んじゃった 本当の悪魔になってもプレイユー
Ah, I died, I died, even if I become a real demon, play you.
あくまで天使じゃん？ 最強じゃん！
After all, I'm an angel, right? The strongest, right!
ずっといっしょ！
Always together!
充電器を貸して！ またあなたのせいであたし蘇生減った
Lend me a charger! Because of you again, my revival count decreased.
終電見逃して！ またあたしのせいで帰れなくなった
Missed the last train! Because of me again, I couldn't get home.
繋がっていようね
Let's stay connected, okay?
繋がってようね
Let's stay connected.
息も打ちこんで
Holding our breath too.
お互いに足を引っ張り合おう
Let's drag each other down.
沈殿した想いを燃やして　ずっと一緒
Burning our sedimented feelings, together forever.
参観日にだって
Even on visiting days,
誰からも見られていない気がしたんだ
I felt like no one was looking at me at all.
散々死に買って　自分の街に期待しないようにしたんだ
After fighting so much, I stopped expecting anything from my town.
そうやって守った孤独さえ　めちゃくちゃになった
Even the loneliness I protected that way became a total mess.
あたし いつだって死にたくてしかたない
I always want to die so badly,
こんな顔大事にしたいと思えないもう
I can no longer cherish a face like this.
共に過ごした日々が
The days we spent together,
ささやかな幸せが
The modest happiness,
かけがえのないトラウマになってたらいいな
I hope they became an irreplaceable trauma.
離れ離れなんて
Being separated like this—
誰かが吐かせたバグだよね
That's just a bug someone spat out, right?
あなたの一生の後悔として　添い遂げるよ
As your lifelong regret, I will stay with you to the end.
大切なものって何？　今無くしたそれ
What is something precious? That which I just lost—
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ
I made a mistake by confusing it with myself.
取り返しがつかないね
There's no going back,
健やかなるときも病めるときも　黒い履歴の中でずっと一緒
in sickness and in health, inside our dark history, together forever.
もうちょっと普通に　悲しいこと悲しいと思いたかった
I wanted to feel sad things as simply sad.
長調のチューンに感情を託して楽になりたかった
I wanted to entrust my emotions to a major tune and find relief.
せめて一生懸命に聞いてくださいね
At least, please listen with all your heart.
あたし いつだって死にたくてしかたない
I always want to die so badly,
あんな歌の言いなりになっていたくないの
I don't want to be at the beck and call of a song like that.
あなただけ一人で　あたしの目を盗んで　幸せになろうなんて思わないで
Don't you dare try to find happiness all by yourself, stealing my gaze.
髪を乾かしてくれた夜から　あたしは壊されたんだよ
Ever since that night you dried my hair, I've been broken.
あなたの一生の後悔として　添い遂げるよ
As your lifelong regret, I will stay with you to the end.
外れなくなってしまった指輪みたいに
Like a ring that can no longer be taken off,
何度もずっとフラッシュバックしている　最低だよ
flashing back over and over again—it's awful.
一緒に居た時の方が　あたし可愛かったなあ
Back when we were together, I was so much cuter.
あなたの一生の後悔として　添い遂げるよ
As your lifelong regret, I will stay with you to the end.
大切なものって何？　今無くしたそれ
What is something precious? That which I just lost—
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ
I made a mistake by confusing it with myself.
取り返しがつかないね
There's no going back,
健やかなるときも病めるときも　他の誰かと眠っていても　呪いの悪夢でずっと一緒
in sickness and in health, even if you sleep with someone else, inside a cursed nightmare, together forever.
教えてもっと　あなたの事
Tell me more about you.
Tell me mo-mo-mo-more, Tell me mo-mo-mo-more
Tell me more more more, Tell me more more more
聞かせてもっと　あなたの声
Let me hear your voice even more.
Let me hi-mo-mo-more, Let me hi-mo-mo-more
Let me hear more more more, Let me hear more more more
こんなドキドキもう抑えきれない
I can't hold back this pounding heart anymore!
All I need you, All I need you
友達は卒業　運命の私見つけて欲しいの
Graduating from friends—I want you to find your destined me!
勇気を出して　じーっ見詰める作戦
Gathering my courage, my steadfast staring strategy!
目と目が合えば　ほうら！
If our eyes meet, hey!
止められない
I can't stop it!
YEAH! YEAH! YEAH!
この恋この愛で
With this love, with this affection,
メールメルティー溶けちゃうよ
melt, melt, I'm gonna melt away!
ねえねね気づいてマイダーリン
Hey, hey, hey, notice me, my darling,
届け大好き！
and receive my love!
アイスクリームアイスクリーム叫びましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's shout it out!
アイスクリームアイスクリーム（Hey!）
Ice cream, ice cream! (Hey!)
アイスクリームアイスクリーム叫びましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's shout it out!
アイスクリームアイスクリーム
Ice cream, ice cream!
ルナちゃん？
Luna-chan?
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
チョコミントよりもあなたっ！
More than chocolate mint, I like you!
わためちゃん？
Watame-chan?
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
ストロベリーフレーバーよりもあなたっ！
More than strawberry flavor, I like you!
おかゆちゃん？
Okayu-chan?
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
クッキー＆クリームよりもあなたっ！
More than cookies and cream, I like you!
みんな！
Everyone!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
もちろん大好きアイスクリーム！
Of course, I love ice cream!
止められない
I can't stop it!
YEAH! YEAH! YEAH!
この恋この愛で
With this love, with this affection,
メールメルティー溶けちゃうよ
melt, melt, I'm gonna melt away!
ねえねね気づいてマイダーリン
Hey, hey, hey, notice me, my darling,
届け大好き！
and receive my love!
アイスクリームアイスクリーム叫びましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's shout it out!
アイスクリームアイスクリーム（Hey!）
Ice cream, ice cream! (Hey!)
叫びましょう
Let's scream it out!
つくり あいすくりーむ！
Make it, ice cream!
お願い つけて マイダリン
I'm begging you, put it on, my darling
お願い 気づいて マイダリン
Please realize it, my darling
勇気を出して
Gather your courage
近づく作戦
A close-up strategy
手と手が触れて
Our hands touch
そう...
Yeah...
とめられない！
Can't be stopped!
イェイ イェイ イェイ この恋 この愛で
Yeah, with this love and affection
メロメロに溶けちゃうよ
It melts you away completely
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ 気づいて マイダリン
Hey, realize it, my darling
それは... あなた！
That is... you!
あいすくりーむ あいすくりーむ 叫びましょう
Ice cream, let's scream it out
つくり あいすくりーむ！
Make it, ice cream!
あいすくりーむ あいすくりーむ 叫びましょう
Ice cream, let's scream it out
つくり あいすくりーむ！
Make it, ice cream!
あいすくりーむ あいすくりーむ 叫びましょう
Ice cream, let's scream it out
つくり あいすくりーむ！
Make it, ice cream!
あいすくりーむ あいすくりーむ 叫びましょう
Ice cream, let's scream it out
つくり あいすくりーむ！
Make it, ice cream!
ラララ... love, love...
La la la... love, love...
魔法みたいな
Magic, it feels like
夢みたいな
Dreaming, it seems like
ファンタジックな物語が
My fantastical story is happening
世界に感染
A pandemic threatening
淫らに蔓延
Happily spreading
待って、そんなの聞いてないってば！
Wait, I've never heard of such a thing!
ダーリン。
Darling.
根本的に 痛い 異常行動
Realistically, this acting up I've seen
支える 枯れない 妄想量
Has got me holding back my daydreaming
本能的に 深い 破壊衝動
Instinctively, my mind is telling me
照らす 確かな 解像度
To break up all the separation I see
恋の導火線 いざ火をともし
Come on and light the fuse that leads to love
ひとつ ここらで本調子
It's rather common here from what I've seen
脳細胞に 今 叩き込め
Now keep it up, get it through your skull
わからないことだらけを
That there's so much you're misunderstanding
あざとい、きわどい 笑わないで
This cunning and cruelty, don't laugh at me
いつもいつも 誤魔化してばっかりね！
You're always trying your best at lying to me!
いらない、知らない おどけないで！
Don't need it, don't know it, don't sugarcoat!
言えない 消えない 思い込め
An unspoken, unfading, unreal thought of
愛の強制ミューティレーション！
Love's automatic mutilation!
魔法みたいな
Magic, it feels like
夢みたいな
Dreaming, it seems like
ファンタジックな物語が
My fantastical story is happening
世界に感染！
A pandemic threatening
不快に蔓延！
Gruesomely spreading
待って、こんなの聞いてないってば、ダーリン？
Wait, you've never seen anything like it, darling?
ベターな恋愛 エラーな展開
Better new romance, errors and plot twists
だって、それじゃつまらないでしょ...
Does it matter how boring they have to be?
切り抜けて
Cutting away now
惹きつけて
Ripping to frays now
愛の顔面ストレート！
Love's way to punch you straight in the face!
根本的に まずい 異常行動
Realistically, this acting up I've seen
支える いかれた 情報量
Has got me holding back my informing
圧倒的に 浅い 母性本能
Instinctively, a faint maternal feeling
暴く 飢えた 奴隷根性
Has me revealing my subserviency
恋の導火線 いざ火をつけて
Come on and light the fuse that leads to love
頭の中は アルデンテ？
Inside your head is getting ardente
生細胞に 今 流し込め
Go on and fill your cup with endurance
耐え難いことだらけを
With there's so much that you can't risk enduring
甘い、きわどい 笑わないで
This freezing connection, don't play games
いつもいつも 当てつけてばっかりね！
You're never gonna come out and say what you think!
つたないうかがい ふざけないで
This question, the stumbling, don't mess around
言えない 消えない 思い込め
An unspoken, unfading, unreal thought of
愛の眼球アイスピック！
Love's easy lobotomization!
好きな人の
The person I hate
好きな人ってだけで嫌い
They're taking our fate and tossing it aside
都合の良い子 演じて一生、終わりたくないんだよ
I've been the good kid all my life
狂った未来に迎合 終わった抵抗
My future teeters on bent, rebellion ending
いっそこのまま目を塞いで
Recommending you keep your eyes closed
切って爽快
Cuts refreshing
喰らって崩壊
Destruction fetching
知って後悔
Voices catching
望んだ将来
Victory retching
手を繋いで 場を繋いで
Touching our bases, saving our places
ファンタジックなすたもんだが積もりに感染 危険に破綻
My fantastical noisy calamity infecting!
待って、こんなの聞いてないってば、おつないで
Wait, you've never seen anything like it?
ファンタジックなすったもんだが積もりに感染 危険に破綻
Better new romance, errors and plot twists
もういいぜ もういいぜ それ
That's enough, that's enough, that's...
もういいぜ もういいぜ 逆に興奮してきたなあ
That's enough, that's enough, I'm getting excited on the contrary
おっけいいね おっけいいね 夢
Okay, sounds good, your dream
おっけいいね おっけいいね
Okay, sounds good, okay, sounds good
景気いいけど 品性は THE END
It's prosperous, but graciousness is the end
Gott ist tot
神っぽいな それ 卑俗
That's god-ish, that's vulgar
神っぽいな それ My God
That's god-ish, that's My God
踏みつけて 焼き付けて 息切れそうな 酸素神経
Stomping and burning, my oxygen nerves are running out of breath
壊れそうな 群れ本能 崩れそうな 秩序の前に
Before the flock instinct that's about to break, before the order that's about to collapse
愛のないレボリューション！
A loveless revolution!
ドキドキ ドキメキ気流に私は乗っている
I'm riding on a heart-pounding, thrilling air current
きっとね
I'm sure of it
なんか言葉にできないこと
Things I can't put into words,
ちょっと心臓騒ぎなこと
things that make my heart flutter a bit,
なんとなく今日を照らすこと
things that somehow illuminate today,
ちょっと好みのお花見つけた！
I found a flower I kind of like!
白い霧ばかりエブリデイ
Everyday is just white fog,
探しものさえ探せないよ uh
I can't even find what I'm looking for, uh.
ワクワクしたようなダイアリー
A diary that feels so exciting,
知らんぷりして放り出すなんて
pretending not to care and throwing it away—
ライアイアイアイアイアリー
Liar-liar-liar-liar-liar-liary!
やらうせなかったハート Wowow
My frustrated heart, wow-oh-oh!
でも、だけどきっと、可能性あり
But, still, surely, there is a possibility!
気持ちいい風に遊泳して うんとすっとちょっともっといつかは飛べたらいいな！
Floating in a pleasant breeze, hopefully I can fly far away someday!
ドキドキ ドキメキ気流に私は乗っている！
I'm riding on a heart-pounding, thrilling air current!
きっとね イエイエイ
I'm sure of it, yeah, yeah, yeah!
わからない物語にビビらないで
Don't be scared of an unknown story,
キラキラ空想に世界が踊る！ 笑ってイエイエイ
the world dances in sparkling daydreams! Smile, yeah, yeah!
チジコマってる時間はないな
There's no time to be cowering in fear,
私を知りたい！
I want to know myself!
何もかもがまだわからないないないない
I still don't know anything at all, na-na-na-na-na!
私を見つけたい！
I want to find myself!
いってきますを声に出せたなら
If I can say "I'm heading out" out loud,
ちょっとだけ大人になったかもね
maybe I've grown up just a little bit.
チャチャカチャカ深呼吸
Cha-cha-chaka-chaka, take a deep breath,
優しくあるたびに失速
losing speed every time I try to be kind.
つまらない筆跡は夢がない
Boring handwriting holds no dreams,
ちょっと嫌な自分見つけた
I found a version of myself I kind of dislike.
白い霧覆うエブリデイ
Everyday covered in black fog,
雨に打たれて帰りたくなるの oh
getting caught in the rain makes me want to go home, oh.
ワクワクしたようなダイアリー
A diary that feels so exciting,
少し浮かんで走り出すなんて
floating up a little and starting to run—
まあいいやいやいやいやいやいやいやいや
well, whatever, whatever, whatever!
しゃかりきで行くハート Wowow
A heart going full throttle, wow-oh-oh!
お気に入りのアクセは失くしたくないの
I don't want to lose my favorite accessory,
Wowow まだ何もわかっていんないんだ
wow-oh-oh, I still don't understand anything yet.
Wowow 好きって気持ちに向かいたい
Wow-oh-oh, I want to embrace the feeling of love,
あの星のように輝きたい ah
I want to shine like that star, ah!
ドキドキ ドキメキ気流に私は乗っている
I'm riding on a heart-pounding, thrilling air current!
やっぱね イエイエイ
I knew it, yeah, yeah, yeah!
答えのない世界で生きてるせいです
It's all because I'm living in a world without answers.
未来は優秀に在ってても変わんないし
Even if the future is brilliant, nothing changes,
叫んでイエイエイ 私らしく体感！
so I'll scream, yeah, yeah, experiencing it my way!
ドキドキ ドキメキ気流を乗り越えた先には イエイエイ
Beyond crossing this heart-pounding, thrilling air current, yeah, yeah,
わからない物語が待っている
an unknown story is waiting for us.
小さな勇気で何者を変えよう！
Let's change something with a little courage!
ねぇ、大切な話があるんだ
Hey, I have an important story to tell you,
ここにない探しものがあるんだ
there's something I'm looking for that isn't here.
だから旅に出ます そのうち帰ります
That's why I'm setting off on a journey, I'll be back soon.
Ooh, ちょっとだけ大人になったかもね
Ooh, maybe I've grown up just a little bit.
チャチャカチャカ深呼吸
Cha-cha-chaka-chaka, take a deep breath,
優しくあるたびに失速
losing speed every time I try to be kind.
つまんない 必死こく つまんない 秘事はない
Boring hard work, boring secret affairs,
ちょっと嫌な自分見つけた
I found a version of myself I kind of dislike.
黒い霧覆うエブリデイ
Everyday covered in black fog,
雨に打たれて帰りたくなるの
getting caught in the rain makes me want to go home.
ワクワクしたようなダイアリー
A diary that feels so exciting,
少し疲れて走り出すなんて
getting a little tired and starting to run—
なんて まいあいいいあいあいあいあー
what, my-ai-ai-ai-ai-ai-air!
しゃかりきで行くハート Wowow
A heart going full throttle, wow-oh-oh!
お気に入りのアクセは失くしたくないの
I don't want to lose my favorite accessory,
Wowow まだ何もわかっちゃいないんだ
wow-oh-oh, I still don't understand anything yet.
Wowow 好きって気持ちに向かいたい
Wow-oh-oh, I want to embrace the feeling of love,
あの星のように輝きたい ah
I want to shine like that star, ah!
ドキドキ ドキメキ気流に私は乗っている
I'm riding on a heart-pounding, thrilling air current!
やっぱね イエイエイ
I knew it, yeah, yeah, yeah!
答えのない世界で生きてるせいです
It's all because I'm living in a world without answers.
未来は優秀に在ってても変わんないし
Even if the future is brilliant, nothing changes,
叫んでイエイエイ 私らしく体感！
so I'll scream, yeah, yeah, experiencing it my way!
ドキドキ ドキメキ気流を乗り越えた先には イエイエイ
Beyond crossing this heart-pounding, thrilling air current, yeah, yeah,
わからない物語が待っている
an unknown story is waiting for us.
小さな勇気で何も変えよう
Let's change something with a little courage!
ねぇ、大切な話があるんだ
Hey, I have an important story to tell you,
ここにない探しものがあるんだ
there's something I'm looking for that isn't here.
だから旅に出ます そのうち帰ります
That's why I'm setting off on a journey, I'll be back soon.
Ooh, ちょっとだけ大人になったかもね
Ooh, maybe I've grown up just a little bit.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明
We are all meaningless.
(Hey!)
ぼくらはみんな意味不明
We are all meaningless.
(Hey!)
夜が明ける 朝目覚める 首痛める
Night breaks, morning awakens, my neck aches.
この身体に自分がいる 君と喋る
I exist in this body, talking to you,
飯を食べる 服を着てる そのすべてが不気味である
eating meals, wearing clothes—everything is eerie.
なんか変だ 変だ 変だ 変だ 駅の改札通り抜ける
It's strange, strange, strange, strange, passing through the station ticket gate.
こんな平和 平和 平和 平和 当たり前でウケル
Such peace, peace, peace, peace—it's too natural, it's funny.
猫の名前は なんとなくタマで 犬の名前は なんとなくポチだ
The cat's name is just Tama, the dog's name is just Pochi.
世界は世界は なんとなく終わりそうで 存在を抱えたまま夕焼けに溶けていくよ
The world, the world, seems to be ending somehow, melting into the sunset holding onto existence.
生きる意味も 頑張る意味も ないないない 無駄かもしれない 千年後何も残らないけど
The meaning of living, the meaning of working—no, no, no, it might be a waste, nothing will remain in a thousand years, but
それでも君と笑っていたい
I still want to be smiling with you.
犬の名前は なんとなくポチだ
The dog's name is somehow Pochi.
世界は なんとなく終わりそうで
The world feels like it's ending somehow,
存在を抱えたまま ゆりゆりに溶けていくよ
holding onto existence as it gently melts away.
生きてる意味も 頑張る意味も ないないない 無駄かもしれない
Meaning in living, meaning in trying—none at all, it might be pointless.
千年後 何も残らないけど それでも君と笑っていたい
A thousand years from now, nothing remains, but even so, I want to laugh with you.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明だから
Because we're all incomprehensible!
月が昇る 星が光る 虫が跳ねる それを見てる
The moon rises, stars shine, insects jump, watching it all.
あれいつからここにいるんだっけ いつまでここでいられるんだっけ
Since when was I here? Until when can I stay here?
何も何にもなれないままで 化け物から逃れてるだけ
Staying unable to become anything, just fleeing from monsters.
知識炉でイメージを浮かべて ストップした思考は敵だらけ
Imagining in the furnace of knowledge, stopped thoughts are full of enemies.
犬の名前は 今でもタロウだ
The dog's name is still Taro.
猫の名前は 今でも花子だ
The cat's name is still Hanako.
時間は なんとなく通り過ぎて ゴミ溜めで埋まったまま 星空を眺めてるよ
Time just passes by somehow, buried in a trash heap, gazing at the starry sky.
愛する意味も 恋する意味も ないないない 嘘かもしれない
Meaning in loving, meaning in romance—none at all, it might be a lie.
1+1もよくわからんけど それでも君を守っていたい
1+1 I don't really understand, but even so, I want to protect you.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明だから
Because we're all incomprehensible!
それでもぼくらは トンネルで息を止める 鳥居で鶴を折る
Even so, we hold our breath in tunnels, fold origami cranes at torii gates,
肉球を触る 横断歩道の白い部分だけを踏む
touch paw pads, and step only on white crosswalks.
それでもぼくらは 間違ったことをする 正しいと思い込む
Even so, we do wrong things, convinced they're right,
頭いいからわかっていた また分かった気になっていたんだ
because we're smart and knew it, yet we felt like we finally understood.
生きてる意味も 頑張る意味も ないないない ないないない
Meaning in living, meaning in trying—none at all, none at all!
ないないないない それでもやるしかない
None at all, but still we have no choice but to do it!
生きてる意味も 頑張る意味も ないないない 無駄かもしれない
Meaning in living, meaning in trying—none at all, it might be pointless.
千年後 何も残らないけど それでも君と笑っていたい
A thousand years from now, nothing remains, but even so, I want to laugh with you.
夢を叶えても 悟り開いても 結局は孤独かもしれない お化けになっても 虚無に帰しても それでも君と笑いたいな
Even if dreams come true, enlightenment reached, loneliness remains. Even in nothingness, I want to laugh with you.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明だから
Because we're all incomprehensible!
そう ぼくらはみんな意味不明
Yes, we're all incomprehensible...
そう簡単な祈りだった 遥かから だんだんと消える感嘆
It was such a simple prayer, an exclamation gradually fading from afar.
今からどん帳が上がるから 静かな会場を後にさようなら
The curtain is about to rise now, so farewell to the quiet venue behind.
Very unexpected to be here
言いかけていたことがひとつ消えて また増えて背中に後ろめたさが残る
Something I was about to say disappeared one by one, leaving guilt on my back.
従いたい 心根を吐き出さぬように込めて 胸の中が織りのように濁る
To avoid spitting out my true feelings, I hold it in, and my heart grows muddy like weave.
受け止めたいことが自分さえ抱えられず もてあましたそれを守っている
I'm protecting what I couldn't even hold myself, things I couldn't handle.
重なった声はからからに二度と生えてうめつくそう 何を言うべきかわからなくて
Overlapping voices dry up and bloom twice—not knowing what to say,
感じてたものが遠く離れ去っていた
what I felt had drifted far away.
同じようで違うんだなんだか気が
They look the same yet different, somehow...
いつまで行こうか どこまで行けるのか 確かじゃないなら何を思うの
How long shall we go, how far can we go? If it's uncertain, what do you think?
僕らが離れるなら 僕らが迷うなら その度に何回も繋がれるように
If we part ways, if we get lost, so that we can reconnect time and time again,
ここにいてくれるなら 話さずいられたら まだ誰も知らない 感覚で救われてく
if you stay here with me, if we could stay without speaking, I'm saved by a sensation no one else knows yet.
Very unexpected to be here
本当は消耗をもって 代わりに成す 実際は当座代わりはなく 楽とは嘘でなる 誇ろ
Truth is, taking on exhaustion to accomplish in return—actually there's no substitute for the present, ease is a lie.
そう簡単な祈りだった
It was such a simple prayer.
端から段々と消える感歎
Admiration gradually fading from the edge.
今から緞帳が上がるから静かな会場を後に
The curtain is about to rise, leaving the quiet venue behind.
さようならと言いかけていた事が一つ消えてまた増えて
The goodbyes I tried to say vanished and returned again,
背中に後ろめたさが残る
Leaving a lingering sense of guilt on my back.
従いたい心根を吐き出せぬように呑み込んで
Swallowing down the obedience I couldn't express,
胸の中が濁流のように濁る
My heart grows muddy like a raging torrent.
受け入れたいことが自分さえ抱えられず持て余した
I couldn't even hold what I wanted to accept,
それを守っている
Yet I protect it still.
掠んだ声はからからに喉を焼いて埋め尽くす
A hoarse voice burns and fills my dry throat.
何を言うべきか分からなくて感じてたものが遠く放たれていた
Not knowing what to say, what I felt was cast far away.
同じ様で違うなんだか違ふ
It looks the same, yet feels somehow different.
君と泣く
Crying with you,
君と笑う
Smiling with you,
君と怒る
Getting angry with you,
君と歌う
Singing with you,
君と踊る
Dancing with you,
君と話す
Talking with you.
いつまで続くだろうと
Wondering how long this will last,
同じように同じように呟く
I murmur the exact same words once more.
今忘れないよう刻まれた空気を
So I won't forget this carved atmosphere,
これから何度思い出すのだろう
I wonder how many times I'll recall it from now on.
僕らが離れるなら
If we are to part,
僕らが迷うなら
If we are to stray,
その度に何回も繋がれるように
So we can be connected again and again each time.
ここに居てくれるなら離さずいられたら
If you're here with me, if I never have to let you go,
まだ誰も知らない感覚で
With a feeling nobody knows yet,
僕の生きるすべてを確かめて正しくして
Confirm and validate everything in my life.
(unhappy?) 悩める人の子よ
(Unhappy?) You troubled child,
(unlucky?) 人成らざる者も
(Unlucky?) Even those not quite human,
(be happy!) 挙って目指せよ
(Be happy!) All together, aim for it,
(undead) 生きているんだし
(Undead) Since we're alive after all.
目を逸した過去も退屈な未来も
The past we averted our eyes from, the boring future too,
カウンセリング やれやれ
Counseling, oh well.
古今東西 ピースピース
East and west, peace, peace.
ねえねえねえねえ 何だかどうして戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
Hey, why does it feel like we're fighting each other?
触れられない触れたこともない過去の自分
A past self I can't touch and have never even touched.
自分自分自分 自分ととっくに死んでる透明な亡霊と対決 幼くて痛い記憶の奥
Me, me, me, me—a showdown with a transparent ghost long dead, deep within childish memories.
残念 もう居ないのに
Regrettable, even though you're no longer here.
あれそっちがいい? アイロニーね
Oh, you prefer that side? How ironic.
透かされてるのは現在の自分? ナンセンス
What's being seen through is my present self? Nonsense.
消えないだってりえす 要はコンプレックス 取り憑かれてるみたい
Can't erase it, that's right. In short, a complex—it's like being possessed.
巻き付いたまま まだ離れない 在りし日の自分
Wrapped tightly around me, the self of days gone by still won't let go.
アンデッド 死んじゃいない お前とお前の連鎖
Undead! You're not dead—you and your chain of existence.
生きていることとは変わり続けることだ
To be alive is to keep on changing.
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ 幸せになろうとしないなんて卑劣だ
Don't just surrender to unhappiness; refusing to find happiness is cowardly.
この世この世は 奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world, this world is a strange, strange fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
Who knows if an ogre or a snake will appear next?
出会って会ってやっと始まる物語
Only after meeting does the story finally begin.
さあ 人か化け物か 閑話休題 ピースピース
Now, human or monster? But enough of that—peace, peace.
なんかどうして未来になんじょなんの
Why on earth is it turning into the future like this?
希望問題できないような気がして
Feeling like no hope is possible whatsoever.
もう充分生きてる 気っ風とテンプレートで食傷 素敵な出来事の気配もない
Lived long enough; fed up with templates, not a single sign of anything wonderful.
残念 積んだ経験の因果 形態化された神話と退屈な進化 要は刺激が欲しいんだ
Too bad—karma of accumulated experience, a formalized myth and boring evolution. I want a thrill.
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった なんて整っていくガイドライン
Got bored, got used to it—guidelines falling smoothly into place.
増えるコンプライアンス 蓋されてくみたい
Increasing compliance, as if being capped and closed off.
吸い尽くして あれもどれもどれも同じ味がする
Sucking it all dry—this, that, and everything else tastes the exact same.
アンデッド 死んじゃいない お前とお前の連鎖
Undead! You're not dead—you and your chain of existence.
何時の世も 過去も未来も 現在にあるんだ
In any era, past and future exist right in the present.
生きていることを愚直に果たすよ 目指せハッピーエンド
Faithfully fulfill being alive—aim for a happy ending.
アンデッド 死んじゃいない おわりに言っているんだ
Undead! You're not dead—I'm telling this to you.
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人であれ ただ苦しみになるって耐えているだけじゃ死んでいるも同質 屍のアンデッド
Don't give up on happiness. Just enduring suffering is practically being dead—a corpse undead.
(unhappy?) 悩める人の子よ
(Unhappy?) You troubled child,
(unlucky?) 人成らざる者も
(Unlucky?) Even those not quite human,
(be happy!) 挙って目指せよ
(Be happy!) All together, aim for it,
(undead) 生きているんだろ
(Undead) Since you're alive after all.
不幸に浸るも 幸せになるのも そう全部全部 お前だ ここんとこ財産が最善の場所 ピースピース
Drenching in misery or finding happiness—it's all you. Right here, peace, peace.
感情なんてもんはどうしても無駄だって悪魔は言った 「何もかも捨てちまえよ」
"Throw everything away," said the devil.
嚔、快不快も、喜怒哀楽さえも!
Ah, even likes and dislikes, even joys and sorrows!
どうしようもない事実、ヒトは終焉から逃れられない
It's an undeniable fact; humans cannot escape from the end.
「誰も抗えない欲望に従え」 思考を進めるな 脳ミソを回せ
"Obey the desires that no one can resist. Don't rest your thoughts, make your brain spin."
「誰もお前のことなど見ちゃいないさ」
"No one is even watching you."
おかしくなってしまうことをどうして恥じる?
Why are you ashamed of going crazy?
お前らに完璧で間違った踊り方を教えてやるから
I'll teach you the perfect, wrong way to dance.
いっせーので捨てちまえ そんな命ならば
So, all at once, throw it away, if that's the kind of life it is.
何十何百何千何万回学習しなさいな
Learn it tens of tens of hundreds of thousands of times.
どうしたってさ 空っぽの頭蓋骨だろう
No matter what, it's an empty skull, isn't it?
感情なんてもいつ何時でも邪魔だって悪魔は言った 「反論の余地などない」
The devil said that emotions are always a nuisance. "There is no room for argument."
嚔、人生に意味を与えておくれ!
Ah, give some meaning to life!
420でさえも救えない終焉がある知った
I learned that there is an end that even 420 cannot save.
「誰も疑わない神様を疑え」 思考を進めるな 脳ミソを回せ
"Doubt the god that no one doubts. Don't rest your thoughts, make your brain spin."
「誰もお前のことなど見ちゃいないさ」
"No one is even watching you."
躊躇している数秒の無益さを知れ
Know the futility of the few seconds you are hesitating.
お前らに完璧で間違った踊り方を教えてやるから
I'll teach you the perfect, wrong way to dance.
いっせーので捨てちまえ そんな命ならば
So, all at once, throw it away, if that's the kind of life it is.
何十何百何千何万回学習しなさいな
Learn it tens of tens of hundreds of thousands of times.
どうしたってさ 頭ん中空っぽなこと分かっていないようだ
No matter what, it seems you know your head is empty.
承認欲求にレイプされ 死んだ花をぶら下げている女
A woman raped by a desire for approval, dangling a dead flower.
何かを愛することすらままならないまま餌を待つだけ
Unable to even love something, just waiting for bait.
踊り方を知らない 芸術の価値などわからない奴らに堕落していれば 何も見えないまま
For those who don't know how to dance, who don't understand the value of art, If you keep depraving, you'll be able to see nothing.
真善美に背いた踊り方を教えてやるから
I'll teach you a way to dance that turns its back on truth, goodness, and beauty.
いっせーので狂っちまえ 惨めな姿で
So, all at once, go crazy, in a miserable figure.
何十何百何千何万何億人の中でさ
Among tens of tens of hundreds of thousands, hundreds of millions of people,
そうして埋もれていたっていいとどうして言えるのだろう?
How can you say it was fine to be buried like that?
ねえ 世界が患っている狂信は 健全者でさえも目が眩むような光を放っている
Hey, the madness that the world is suffering from, Emits a light that dazzles even the healthy.
今夜 悪魔がお前らにこう言うぜ 「神とやらに惑わされるなよ」
Tonight, the devil says this to you all: "Don't be deceived by gods or anything."
感情なんてもんはどうしても無駄だって悪魔は言った 「何もかも捨てちまえよ」
"Throw everything away," said the devil.
嚔、快不快も、喜怒哀楽さえも!
Ah, even likes and dislikes, even joys and sorrows!
どうしようもない事実、ヒトは終焉から逃れられない
It's an undeniable fact; humans cannot escape from the end.
「誰も抗えない欲望に従え」 思考を進めるな 脳ミソを回せ
"Obey the desires that no one can resist. Don't rest your thoughts, make your brain spin."
「誰もお前のことなど見ちゃいないさ」
"No one is even watching you."
おかしくなってしまうことをどうして恥じる?
Why are you ashamed of going crazy?
お前らに完璧で間違った踊り方を教えてやるから
I'll teach you the perfect, wrong way to dance.
いっせーので捨てちまえ そんな命ならば
So, all at once, throw it away, if that's the kind of life it is.
何十何百何千何万回学習しなさいな
Learn it tens of tens of hundreds of thousands of times.
どうしたってさ 空っぽの頭蓋骨だろう
No matter what, it's an empty skull, isn't it?
ねえ 世界が患っている狂信は 健全者でさえも目が眩むような光を放っている
Hey, the madness that the world is suffering from, Emits a light that dazzles even the healthy.
今夜 悪魔がお前らにこう言うぜ 「神とやらに惑わされるなよ」
Tonight, the devil says this to you all: "Don't be deceived by gods or anything."
感情なんてもんはどうしても無駄だって悪魔は言った 「何もかも捨てちまえよ」
"Throw everything away," said the devil.
嚔、快不快も、喜怒哀楽さえも!
Ah, even likes and dislikes, even joys and sorrows!
どうしようもない事実、ヒトは終焉から逃れられない
It's an undeniable fact; humans cannot escape from the end.
はい です！かあー
Yes, it is! Ah~
まずはみんなに見ていただきたいCMがございます！
First, we have a commercial we'd like everyone to see!
やばいみんなこころして...どうぞ！
Oh no, everyone brace yourselves... Here it goes!
ここからは檜山修之が、猫又おかゆ誕生日記念2026のグッズを紹介するぞ！まずはお前だ！
From here on, Nobuyuki Hiyama will introduce the merchandise for Nekomata Okayu's 2026 Birthday! First is this!
はっぴ〜おかゆはっぴ〜
Happy Okayu Happy!
神岡ちろる先生の描き下ろしイラストが描かれたはっぴがグッズになったぞ！
An illustration specially drawn by Chiroru Kamioka has been turned into a Happi coat!
きょとん顔のおかゆんがとてもキュート！
A blank-faced Okayu-n is super cute!
イベントやライブに着ていけば、一目でのおぎやあピールできるスーパーハッピーなグッズだ！！
Wear it to events or lives to proudly show off you're an onigya at a glance—a super happy item!
お出かけに連れてってアクリルスタンド！
Take-along-on-outings Acrylic Stand!
アクスタはもう家に飾るだけの時代じゃない！日々のお出かけを彩る、推し活マストアイテム。
Acrylic stands aren't just for displaying at home anymore! A must-have oshi-katsu item to brighten up your daily outings.
ポーチに入れて外に持ち運んで、おかゆんに世界を沢山見せてあげてくれよな！
Put it in a pouch, take it outside, and show Okayu-n plenty of the world!
ごくごく！BIGたんばら〜
Gulp gulp! BIG tumbler~
甘城なつき先生描き下ろしのミニキャラが描かれた大容量のタンブラー。
A large-capacity tumbler featuring mini-characters specially drawn by Natsuki Amashiro.
持ち手やストローもついているので、外出時はもちろん、勉強中や仕事中、様々なシチュエーションで大活躍間違いなし！
With a handle and straw, it's guaranteed to be a huge hit when going out, studying, working, and in various situations!
おかゆんの配信を見る時にも使ってくれ！！
Be sure to use it when watching Okayu-n's streams too!!
おでかけおにぎり型ショルダーポーチ！
Take-out Onigiri-shaped Shoulder Pouch!
アクスタやhololive friends to Goなどちょっとした小物が入る優れたショルダーポーチだぜ。
An excellent shoulder pouch that fits small items like acrylic stands and Hololive Friends to Go.
透明素材なので日々の推し活に使える一品となっているぞ！
Made of transparent material, it's a piece you can use for your daily oshi activities!
そして...フルセット購入特典はこちら！
And... here is the full-set purchase bonus!
なんとフルセットを購入した全員に、猫又おかゆ直筆サイン＆複製メッセージ入りポストカードがついてくる！
Everyone who purchases the full set will receive a postcard with Nekomata Okayu's handwritten signature & duplicated message!
おにぎりゃーのみんな絶対ゲットしてくれよな！
All you Onigirya, make sure to get your hands on it!
よほ〜い！ふう...
Yohoi! Whew...
ということで、あの〜檜山修之さんに生誕グッズのCMを撮っていただきましたやばい！
So, um... Nobuyuki Hiyama-san filmed the commercial for the birthday goods... Seriously amazing!
お檜山修之さんというね、あのレジェンドの声優さんがいらっしゃって、猫又おかゆホロライブデビュー時からの世界で一番大好きな声優さんと
Nobuyuki Hiyama-san, you know, that legendary voice actor, came along, and Nekomata Okayu—ever since her Hololive debut—has been the biggest fan of him in the entire world, and...
なっております！あのこの場をお借りして、あの檜山修之さん本当にありがとうございました！
...and that's how it is! Taking this opportunity, thank you so much, Nobuyuki Hiyama-san!
ふう、ちょっと興奮、冷めやらぬなんですけど、あのCMにあった通り猫又おかゆ生誕グッズ2026を発売させていただきますので
Phew, I'm still a bit overexcited, but as seen in the commercial, we'll be releasing Nekomata Okayu's 2026 Birthday Goods,
みなさんぜひご予約お待ちしてます！
so everyone, please look forward to pre-ordering!
そして、告知は1つだけじゃないんですね〜。続きましてこちら！とどーん！
And, that's not the only announcement~! Next up is this! Ta-da!
いよいよおまちかね、来月3月26日木曜日に「おかゆにゅう〜R」
At long last, next month on Thursday, March 26th, 'Okayu Nium - R'...
あ〜る！あ〜る！あ〜る！おかゆにゅうむあ〜るがリリース！
...R! R! R! 'Okayu Nium - R' is releasing!
青森を舞台にキミと二人で商品開発という名の恋人旅行がスタート！笑いあり、デートあり、ヤキュウ権もあり？な、盛りだくさんの作品となっております！
Set in Aomori, a romantic trip disguised as product development starts with just the two of you! It's packed with laughs, dates, and even rock-paper-scissors strip games...?
自分で、自分でさ、ヤキュウ権あ〜りって何って、おもちゃだね、うん。自分で言っときながらね、僕がヤキュウ権ありたいてい言っときながらね、
Wait, saying 'rock-paper-scissors strip games' myself... what is that? It's just a toy, yeah. Even though I said it myself, even though I was the one who wanted to have strip games in it,
そしてヤキュウ権あんのにセロ審査大丈夫なのかよというお声、あのたびたびいただいておりますが、なんと心配していたセロ審査も無事シー！で、決まりました！
and people kept asking me, 'Is CERO rating okay even with strip games?', but amazingly, CERO approval—which we were worried about—was successfully passed with a C! It's decided!
ふう、よかったよかった。うん。そして、みんな体験版ももうすでに遊んでくれたかな？
Whew, thank goodness, thank goodness. Yeah. Also, has everyone already played the trial version?
あのドキドキの続きはぜひキミの目で確かめてほしいな！まだまだたくさんの未公開情報もあるとのことなので、おかゆにゅうむあ〜るから目が離せないよ！ぜひお楽しみに！
I hope you'll check out the thrilling continuation with your own eyes! There's still plenty of unreleased information, so you won't be able to take your eyes off Okayu Nium - R! Please look forward to it!
そしてこちら最後の告知となります！毎年発表させていただいているんですが、今日もライブの最後に新曲を発表させていただきます！やったー！
And here is the final announcement! As we announce every year, today at the very end of the live stream, we will announce a new song! Yay!
やっと言えた！今回はですね、ケンユウさんに作詞作曲をしていただきました！ありがとうございますケンユウさん！
I was finally able to say it! This time, Kenyu-san wrote and composed the song for us! Thank you so much, Kenyu-san!
ではでは、あの、いろいろ言いたいこととかもあるんですが、
Well then, um, there are various things I'd like to say, but...
まずはキミの目でしっかりと聞いていただければなと、見ていただければなと思っております。
first of all, I hope you'll listen carefully with your own eyes... I mean, watch with your own eyes.
ではでは、聞いてください。「ノンデリシャス」。
Now then, please listen to "Nondelicious".
今日も噛む噛む 1, 2, 3
Chewing and chewing today too, 1, 2, 3
舌も踊るよ 1, 2, 3
My tongue dances too, 1, 2, 3
トラウマをじっくりにこんだボルシチどうぞ
Please have some borscht simmered thoroughly with trauma
キミの心臓は剥がれたらけさ
Your heart is all peeled off
苦肉のステーキとセルフィッシュ＆チップス
Desperation steak and selfish & chips
マネリーを刻んだサラダ
Salad chopped with money
こんなにもおいしい食卓 邪魔しないで
Don't disturb such a delicious dinner table
お口を開けてはい、あーん
Open your mouth, say "Ah"
ウェーター・ウェーター お皿を下げないで
Waiter, waiter, don't clear the plate
これがボクのおいしいものなんだから
Because this is my delicious meal
ハングリーノングラトニー 新しいメニュー
Hungry non-gluttony, new menu
みんなクワイエット・クライエット お待ちかね
Everyone quiet, quiet, waiting for it
デ・デ・デ・デリシャス デリ・デリシャス
De-de-de-delicious, deli-deli-delicious
ノン・デ・デ・デリシャス デリ・デリシャス
Non-de-de-delicious, deli-deli-delicious
そんなテリボテボけっとばして
Kick away such terrible bowls
エブリデイエブリナイト がっかないで
Don't be disappointed every day every night
ノンデリシャス なんべんだって おかわり
Nondelicious, seconds no matter how many times
お皿積み上げ 3, 4, 5
Stacking plates 3, 4, 5
バベルみたいに 3, 4, 5
Like Babel 3, 4, 5
喉の奥につかえて窒息しかけても
Even if it gets stuck in my throat and I almost choke
大人は飲み込むらしい すごいね
Adults apparently swallow it. Amazing.
見栄切ったのそで きり人情サンドイッチ
Sleeves of false bravado, human-feeling sandwich
情熱の冷めたスープ
Cooled soup of passion
そんなもの頼んでないから
I didn't order anything like that
ボクはボクで好きなものだけ食べるだけ
So I'll just eat what I like
ウェーター・ウェーター 際限なく持ってきて
Waiter, waiter, bring me endlessly
これがボクのおいしい日々なんだから
Because these are my delicious days
色波乱もろもろ飲み込んだあとで
After swallowing all sorts of turbulence
挑めダイエット・ダイエット
Challenge diet, diet
一心不乱に噛む 噛む 不条理を噛む
Chewing with single-minded devotion, chewing absurdities
のらりくらり 幸せそうな顔して
Drifting along with a happy face
噛む 噛む あくまで噛む
Chewing, chewing, chewing to the end
みんなクワイエット・クライエット お待ちかね
Everyone quiet, quiet, waiting for it
デ・デ・デ・デリシャス デリ・デリシャス
De-de-de-delicious, deli-deli-delicious
ノン・デ・デ・デリシャス デリ・デリシャス
Non-de-de-delicious, deli-deli-delicious
そんなテリボテボけっとばして
Kick away such terrible bowls
エブリデイエブリナイト がっかないで
Don't be disappointed every day every night
ノンデリシャス でもなんべんだって おかわりしよう
Nondelicious, but let's have seconds no matter how many times
おにぎりゃーん！！
Onigiryaan!!
今日は祝ってくれてほんとにありがとう…！
Thank you so much for celebrating with me today...!!
毎日がハッピーなのもみんなのおかげで、ずーーっと一緒にいたいね…♡
Every day is happy thanks to everyone, I want to be together forever...♡
ちょっとでも君の笑顔のきっかけになれますように…
猫又おかゆ
I hope this can bring even a small smile to your face...
- Nekomata Okayu